<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<portfolio>
	<section>
		Summer
		<entry>
			<date>July 24, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today in the morning Eric taught us about recursion, which we did did using JavaScript. He then challenged us to 
				make the Koch Snowflake, a fractal generated recursively. I have finished this, but I have yet to finish the 
				styling for the site, and it is not on my website yet. I also have yet to put up my bookmark and stock market websites, 
				which also have more styling work to be done. In the afternoon, I shoulder surfed the Web Design workshop, which was 
				very entertaining.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 23, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today in the morning Amal taught us AJAX, which we used to start a new project. The project used JQuery to 
				access data about stocks from Amal's website. The site then displayed the data as a table. I have yet to 
				finish, though it is likely that I will be able to finish this week. In the afternoon, we discussed 
				Electrical Engineering, which I found very fun. Using a capacitor, some resistors, a battery, and a 555 timer, 
				we were able to make an LED flicker on and off. I also received more parts to make a binary LED counter, which 
				I will work on at home.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 22, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today the class covered regular expressions. I was documenting while the class covered regular expressions, so 
				I missed out on the lesson. Luckily, I had already familiarized myself with regular expressions. After a quick 
				refresher, I was able to catch myself up to speed. In the afternoon, we covered structural engineering again. 
				We worked in teams to create towers that would support marbles in a cup. I worked with Rebecca to make a tower 
				that was 28.5cm from the base to the cup and supported 114 marbles without falling, though we counted the score 
				at 90 marbles. Luckily, we got first.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 21, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today marked the beginning of the third block. We began our advanced programming unit, which covered JavaScript 
				classes and objects. Sadly, I was shoulder surfing for the morning workshop and I missed the concepts covered. 
				In the afternoon we began our unit on engineering, where we used legos and an online applet to learn about 
				the center of gravity of structures. We also used a bridge applet to create structures that would support 
				certain loads.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 18, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we continued our underling work, attempting to convert more files Levi had requested. Much to our 
				disappointment, many of the files we had converted were incorrectly converted. Phil also mentioned creating 
				a bookmark page, which would use mySQL to store a list of bookmarks. Hopefully I will be able to do this even 
				with more projects coming next block. I look forward to the future.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 17, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we continued using mySQL. Joel taught us how to create views of tables, which function similarly 
				to tables themselves. He also discussed 'JOIN' further, and covered 'LIKE'. I missed a few things he 
				said as I had to watch the workshop kids on their break. I finished my Reader website, which is in my 
				portfolio. Ishann, myself, and other apprentices were finally able to finish the task Eric assigned 
				to us for Levi.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 16, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we worked with mySQL again, using PHP to look at joined tables in the browser. I have not 
				yet incorporated these principles into a project, though I will hopefully do so soon. I began 
				working on a project that was prompted by Phil, a page that would run through individual words 
				of a paragraph, inspired by Spritz. Later in the day, Eric graciously assigned me, Ishaan and Rebecca 
				(and later, others as well) the task of converting Word Documents into HTML files. This was 
				likely the most fun I've had in years.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 15, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we continued to use mySQL, working on linking tables as well as continuing to familiarize 
				ourselves with mySQL. I finished my Dynamic Pages site, fixing my CSS and cleaning up the layout, 
				and it is now in my portfolio. I will likely be assigned another task by Phil or Joel soon. I 
				spent the afternoon documenting the "Modeling your World" workshop, and it was great to see younger 
				kids learning the same models and modeling principles I've learned in the past. 
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 14, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today, Joel taught us about mySQL, which we may use for a project related to databases. I find it 
				fairly interesting, and I hope to learn more about it. I also worked on my PHP Dynamic Pages site, 
				which I modeled after Mad Libs. It has not been finished, as I need to fix problems with styling 
				and regular expressions. I decided to learn these today, as I wanted to differentiate 'a' from 'an'. 
				I will probably finish it tomorrow.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 11, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today I completed my PHP dice statistics site. I also converted my blog to an XML file, using PHP to 
				extract from the file. I have one PHP assignment to complete, and I'll be able to complete it next 
				week. I'll also be going back and touching up my other assignments, mixing my HTML and PHP more. 
				It's been a fun and productive first week at Shodor and I look forward to the next topic we cover.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 10, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today I finished my PHP background selector, which is now in my portfolio. I began work on my PHP dice 
				roller, which I have finished the basics of. I hope to add a chart that can scale itself based on the 
				data given, as well as the capability to switch between viewing the raw data and the chart. Hopefully, 
				I can come up with other ways to improve the tool. I also spent some time helping people with their own PHP.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 9, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today I continued to work on my PHP calendar, which I have finished and put on my portfolio page. I also 
				began and finished Dane Joe, which was less challenging especially now that I feel more comfortable putting 
				PHP and HTML together. I have begun work on a background selector, which I believe I can finish soon. I 
				was also able to help a few people with their own calendars and other various PHP projects.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 8, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today Joel taught us basic PHP, which we used to create a random hexadecimal color code generator. We also 
				began working on our PHP projects. I chose to work on the calendar, which is proving to be quite difficult 
				due to issues with PHP and the input itself. Hopefully I can find an alternative, if not a solution. I also 
				spent today helping other people with Subversion, HTML, and their own PHP projects.
			</content>

		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>July 7, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today begins the second block, and my first day at Shodor since April. I was very excited to come back and 
				continue to learn all sorts of things. Today we discussed Subversion, which is what we'll use to keep track 
				of changes and revisions in our upcoming projects. We discussed some command line and vim topics alongside 
				Subversion, as it is run in command line. I look forward to the rest of the week, and the weeks to come.
			</content>

		</entry>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		Spring
		<entry>
			<date>April 5, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we continued our programming projects. I added a great deal of functionality to our model, giving the 
				user the ability to resize the forest, change the forest to a grid, and displaying the burn radius circle 
				on the cursor. I also helped make the graphics for the trees using GIMP. I've definitely learned a lot 
				from this project, and I am definitely looking forward to presenting our project on the 12th.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>March 29, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we began our programming projects, which will be written in Javascript. We will be modeling the spread of 
				a forest fire based on a number of variables, including the number of trees, arrangement of trees, spread 
				probability of the fire, etc. This will be completed and presented on the 12th, and hopefully by then 
				our model will be functional and understandable. I hope to learn much from this project.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>March 15, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we continued discussion of parallel thinking and computing. We learned how to boot BCCD on the machines, 
				as well as how to write algorithms for parallelization of tasks. Aaron and Phil taught the lessons on coding 
				in C, which we then compiled and ran in the terminal. Vikram and Elise, two Shodor interns, taught us about 
				more parallel computing concepts including data vs task parallelization and diminishing returns.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<date>March 8, 2014</date>
			<content>
				Today we discussed a multitude of topics. Aaron and Patricia covered parallel computing in BCCD, which we used 
				to compile and run code, as well as discuss parallel thinking. Mobeen taught the class about computer hardware, 
				and led an activity on finding a computer build under a certain price value, which I found quite interesting. 
				Phil helped the class with parallel computing, and Iain taught us about Conway's Game of Life, which is quite 
				interesting on BCCD.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  <date>March 1, 2014</date>
		  	  <content>
				  Today we discussed parallel computing using bootable cluster CDs. We familiarized ourselves with the Linux 
		  		  terminal, and used it to run different simulations, including one that modeled a pandemic and another modeling 
		  		  the formation of a galaxy. We also covered the pros and cons of using multiple processors and shared vs. 
		  		  distributed memory, which I found very interesting.
			  </content>

		</entry>
		<entry>
		  <date>February 1, 2014</date>
		  	  <content>
		  		  Today we presented our modeling projects to the class. I am confident we did well with ours, as we were able to 
		  		  explain our model well and answer all related questions. I was also happy to see the other models 
		  		  that had been made. After our presentations, we covered basic programming techniques with Safari's Javascript 
		  		  console. Hopefully, we will be able to further explore programming concepts.
			  </content>

		</entry>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		Fall
		<entry>
		  <date>December 14, 2013</date>
		  	<content>
		  		Today is the last Shodor session before we have to present our projects on February the 1st. Our project is done, 
		  		and I do not think we will have to continue work on our optional workday. I am eager to present, and 
		  		I am looking forward to seeing the projects of other groups. I also worked on my HTML project and helped others with theirs, 
		  		though I ended up not changing much on my website.
			</content>

		</entry>
		<entry>
		  <date>December 7, 2013</date>
		  	<content>
		 		Today we began work on our modeling projects. I worked with my partner Luis, and with hard work we finished our model 
		  		even with many problems concerning the size of our model. We collected data for our project as well, and will use this data 
		 		for our presentation. We will continue working on our project next week, and I look forward to our presentation.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  <date>November 23, 2013</date>
		  	<content>
		 		Today we watched Ron's presentation on Business Ethics. We were assigned a Business Ethics assignment alongside 
		  		our HTML and modeling projects. Joel taught as well, covering how to connect to Shodor servers from other computers. 
		 	 	I also worked on my HTML project, reorganizing files and changing layouts. I am looking forward to the modeling project, 
		  		on which we will begin working on the 7th and 14th of December.
			</content>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  <date>November 16, 2013</date>
		  	<content>
				Today we began learning modeling in both Vensim and AgentSheets. Having been part of SSP, I have already been exposed 
				to these techniques; however, I do think it was good practice for a topic I learned almost a year ago. Using the modeling 
				software, we modeled hunger and the factors influencing it, as well as disease and how it spreads. I also worked on my HTML 
				project and I am looking forward to working on our modeling projects, in which the skills we learned today to make our own models 
				and present them.
			</content>
		</entry>
	</section>
</portfolio>